What’s your favourite genre of film?
你最喜欢的电影类型是什么？
For many people who love being petrified, or scared out of their wits, by jump scares that answer will be horror.
对于许多喜欢被突然惊吓吓到目瞪口呆，魂飞魄散的人来说，答案一定是恐怖片。
Whether it’s splatter films, wastelands in the apocalypse, monsters like demons, zombies, vampires, werewolves or phantoms, there’s something to suit everyone’s taste.
无论是血腥暴力片、末日荒原题材，还是恶魔、僵尸、吸血鬼、狼人、幽灵这类怪物形象，恐怖片的题材丰富多样，总能满足不同人的喜好。
But just why do people enjoy watching these terrifying films?
但人们究竟为什么会喜欢看这些令人毛骨悚然的电影呢？
First off, being scared can give us a rush of adrenaline. The heart starts pumping, making these films exhilarating.
首先，恐惧的感觉能让我们肾上腺素飙升，心跳加速，让看这类电影的过程变得刺激十足。
But the fact you’re actually at home safe on the sofa makes the experience of being frightened all the more enjoyable because what’s happening to the characters on the screen is far removed from your experience of being in your living room eating popcorn. It feels more thrilling.
而实际上你正安安稳稳地坐在家里的沙发上，这种安全的环境会让恐惧感变得更加有趣——毕竟屏幕上角色的遭遇，和你在客厅吃着爆米花的现实生活相去甚远，也因此更惊险刺激。
Coltan Scrivner, a PhD candidate in the Department of Comparative Human Development at The University of Chicago, argues that people who watch horror films learn how to regulate their anxiety.
芝加哥大学比较人类发展系的博士生科尔坦·斯克里夫纳认为，观看恐怖片能让人学会调节自身的焦虑情绪。
A study that he co-authored found that horror fans exhibited greater resilience during the early stages on the Covid-19 pandemic than those who didn’t.
他参与撰写的一项研究发现，在新冠疫情初期，恐怖片爱好者比不看恐怖片的人表现出更强的心理韧性。
Also, some horror fans think they could survive the events on screen. That gives those viewers a sense of superiority.
此外，部分恐怖片爱好者认为自己能在电影里的绝境中活下来，这种想法会让他们产生一种优越感。
We often mock the typical tropes of horror films. Why do they try to escape the masked killer by running upstairs and confining themselves?
我们常常会吐槽恐怖片的经典套路：为什么角色要往楼上跑，把自己困在那里躲避蒙面杀手？
The characters often make terrible decisions that lead to their deaths – decisions we as viewers believe we wouldn’t make.
片中角色总是做出致命的糟糕决定，而观众们都觉得换作是自己，绝不会犯这样的错。
So, whether it’s to help people regulate their anxiety, be thrilled by getting scared, or to feel superior mocking the decisions of the characters, there are many reasons people love watching horror films – and if they really scare you, maybe it’s best to watch them with the lights on.
所以，无论是为了调节焦虑情绪、享受惊吓带来的刺激感，还是为了吐槽角色的愚蠢决定而获得优越感，人们喜欢看恐怖片的原因多种多样。不过如果恐怖片真的把你吓得不轻，或许还是开着灯看比较好。